it is official
the game of demise has begun welcome
back to another episode of hermitcraft
and things are about to get dangerous
and i've got to admit there are some
comments last episode saying that i
looked a little bit like winnie the pooh
and i've gotta admit i kinda i kinda do
in the gold armor i think it i think it
fits i look cute anyway let's take a
look at who has oh my goodness
that is 17 lots let's take a look at the
sign up list
me corrales joe hills t tfc uh jevin
stress false mumbo b-dubs clear human
clio
that looks like
pretty much
everyone there's a couple of people not
on here and one of which i have to do
myself which is good times
with scar he's a little bit under the
weather at the moment so he asked me to
sign him up for him which i've now done
so what i'm going to do is put the sign
up in listed so scar scar can pay later
on but the point is he signed up that
makes it 18 people
are in the game of demise 18 people
that's pretty much the entire server
and i thought now to show that the game
has officially begun
what we can do is take the hand and turn
it upside down
so that it's actually
holding the diamonds there we go the
hand has been oh wait
i uh i forgot the thumb
that is a very very broken thumb right
there let's fix that up as well so what
we're gonna do is we're gonna take all
of these diamonds wow i don't even have
enough space for them we're gonna take
all of these diamonds and we're gonna
craft them up into
diamond blocks
whoa
this is a big reward a really big reward
whoever wins this game is going to be in
for
a stack and a half of diamond blocks
that's insane so to show off what the
prize is i thought what i'd do is make a
big pile of diamonds kind of like what's
outside the front of sahara
there we go that is a really decent pile
of diamonds actually i kind of like the
way that that looks so that is the prize
pool the skeleton hand is holding all of
the riches that will be won and of
course when scar pays when he's back at
it then we will add a few more blocks to
that as well so since this is kind of a
new game i also had to clarify a couple
of things so at the end i wrote some
extra points totems of undying are
allowed and mini game deaths count as
deaths in this game as well just so it
clarifies and i can see that the totem
of undying thing has led to a very
conveniently placed totem of a dying
shop which actually is a really good
idea i'm actually gonna buy one right
now yeah looks like looks like someone's
gonna make a lot of diamonds here using
a totem of undying in a very panicky
situation can be quite difficult so if
you want to play it safe hold a totem in
your hand at all time in your off hand
if not well just have it on you now that
the game's begun i'm going to list
everyone who is alive and so far that's
pretty much everyone there's only two
people that aren't involved and that's
wells and python everyone else is
involved in the game which is actually
pretty insane that's gonna make this
game absolutely amazing
i had to put corrales's face just above
the book
it kind of looks like a screaming
bookcase now
okay so that is everyone alive nobody
has died yet but it's only been one day
so i wouldn't expect it i'm gonna leave
the armor here and then when people die
we'll create a little death area here as
well to show who's on the alive team and
then who has unfortunately perished and
lost the game oh i totally forgot about
mum where was i didn't put mumbo's head
there we go and that is the start
officially of the demise game i'm so
shocked and i'm happy that so many
people are involved this is going to be
really interesting now speaking of big
piles of diamonds you'll remember that
at sahara we actually showcased out all
of our diamonds outside the front and
you'll remember that
captain green up here was selling these
sahara memberships by showing off these
example boxes well now that that
competition is done and i actually found
that there's another sale in here
so we can add this to the pile of
diamonds and we can put all of this in
sahara now and i'll have to find a new
purpose for this blimp because if you
actually go up here there's there's a
lot of space up here that's uh
gone to waste a little bit and while
we're here before we go back to sahara i
want to actually put in these treasure
tokens that i've found they're just
lying around so i've been collecting
them so let's see if we can get some
diamonds
[Music]
okay number two
we're not having much luck
[Music]
yay a diamond
man
no luck on the tokens right last last
one
nah no luck for winnie the pooh today
let's head back to sahara and put these
boxes in the system and sell them for a
few more diamonds
i think in this in this little tunnel
here a lot of us like to fly and it's
actually quite dangerous like that you
hit the walls and these trap doors on
the side
they can be quite dangerous if you hit
them so we might have to make a safer
tunnel because dying here does happen
occasionally but i'm going to prove to
all of you that i'm not going to be the
first one to go no sir okey doke here we
are let's put in all of these sahara
deals
one two three four there we go sahara
now has a few more deals it's so
difficult to keep this thing topped up
it doesn't matter how much stuff we put
in here people just buy and buy and buy
look at this buy and buy and buy let's
actually add these to the big diamond
pile that we're making 14 more diamond
blocks
to add
to the pile i was thinking what we could
do
using this hollow thing here is we can
actually make a safe house a bunker that
goes directly underneath and will keep
us safe in the game of demise this can
be a
well a safe house for the long run it's
obviously going to take a long time to
make something like this but i thought
what better place to hide it than under
the diamonds so i'm gonna have to create
some kind of
redstone system to get in here and keep
this as hidden as possible and maybe i
can even get the other sahara fellas in
on this because none of us have died yet
iskalmi and mumbo and we could create
some sort of sahara bunker down here so
what we're going to do
is well dig a hole and then make an a
secret safe underground base and one of
the first things we need to install
is some safety measures we need a beacon
with some regeneration and strength so
if we're ever discovered we've got a lot
of protection behind us i'm not actually
sure if there's anything down here
i probably shouldn't be digging oh aha
it's the jungler cookie this this goes
straight into the jungler hideout oh man
okay so
we can go maybe this deep
we can make this multi-layered that's
not a problem wait what's here
oh this is the jangler thing okay so as
long as we take this the other direction
it will be absolutely fine so as long as
we take the bunker
this way
we probably hopefully maybe won't run
into anything yeah there doesn't seem to
be any issues here wait what is it with
running into absolutely everything
that's the shulker building right there
okay so we we've already limited the
size of this bunker maybe this isn't the
best place or maybe it is a great place
because people won't be expecting it
well anyway this only needs to be the
first room we can make this bigger as we
go on
so
let's start mining this out in a little
bit of a time lapse and see what we can
get done
so i actually started off this time
lapse underground so you can see on the
right that there's false's shop that's
in the way and then on the left there's
the jangler thing that's in the way so
this bunker room had to be fit directly
in between those two things but there is
plenty of space further down and to the
right underneath the shulker shop but
what we've got here is a very i guess
simple and in theme
entrance to the bunker
so this is the first room of our bunker
now this is actually quite a large room
but that's because i want to put in a
couple of beacons that are going to help
us survive with regen and
strength and all that kind of stuff so
what i'm also thinking is that here's
the giant architect logo and we need to
make this a little staircase downwards
because because of the way that this is
positioned between two different shops
we've got the jangler thing over there
we got the shulker box over there we
actually need to go deeper down and move
it to the side so we're going to create
a little staircase that's going to go
down to the rest of the bunker and
that's actually going to be the main
part of the bunker not up here this is
basically just the hello welcome to my
bunker chamber we're going to be working
on this for a few months and you know
what
we may
and i'm just going to look around
make sure no one's watching we may
actually
do a proper item storage here like a a
real one a redstone one crazy i know
or we might not we'll see how things go
i'm not entirely sure what we're going
to put in this bunker but we want it to
be safe and the other benefit of this is
that there's plenty of space here to add
some defensive traps in here in case we
die
i don't plan on dying straight away and
i'm hoping that mumbo and iskall are in
the same boat
and they will help me make this
defendable
so once i've got this trim sorted out
around the bunker we're gonna go and
find ourselves some beacons
now i'm not actually entirely sure where
all the beacons have gone but i know
where one is
that i had ages ago in my base and i
haven't touched it since the start of
the season which is kind of crazy
it's actually underneath my base and
hold on
do you fear the unknown someone's built
something in my base
wait
has someone died already
has anyone
no i don't think anyone has died i've
i've not seen anyone on to be honest
do you fear the unknown
and there's a button
i'm going to be such an easy target for
this game because i have to press the
button well those are wither skulls so
we'll take those
okay okay
if
okay i'm gonna press it just because you
know
i can't help myself
but this is definitely some sort of
demise trap so it could be someone who's
already died and they're already making
traps if so that's very quick
okay if i die from this i will not rest
until i get every other single person go
was it just xp
oh it's an xp machine
oh this is brilliant i actually i really
need to fix up my pickaxes
it just keeps going
there's there's so much xp oh no there
we go we've hit the end and nothing bad
happened
oh my goodness
i mean he chased my nxp
i didn't know he could do this well i've
managed to pretty much mend everything
that i've got so
thanks whoever did that
and also no thank you you scared the
life out of me
all right now we could take this down
that we know what it is
i've drained it of all of its potions
phew okay why was i here oh yeah i was
here for my beacon which is actually oh
it's just here
yes i'm here for my beacon
which is
why on earth did i make a beacon
out of gold blocks and is the beacon
actually even here the actual beacon
block that's the one i need yeah the
beacon's still here okay so we're gonna
take all of this
with us and put it in the new bunker why
was i so silly look at all these gold
blocks i could have used for carrots why
is there a mechanism here
oh
no no no no no no not the portrait man
cave
oh
oh i think i'm smarter than i look
hello old friend
i think we should leave here man it's
been a while it's been a while since
we've been here it's it's a bit
overgrown
let's just leave here and uh pretend
like we didn't see anything
it's cracked
has someone been in here
the poultry man cave has been
neglected this is what happens when you
go on holiday for months on end
does this what does this mean all right
let's just let's get out of here
poor poultry man
the main thing is that i have my beacon
are you poultry man
are you the real portrait man i don't
think i've ever seen one of these just
chilling in my base you know sahara is
becoming extraordinarily big it started
off with this in the warehouse and now
it's extended here we've got a secret
little area under there for village
trading we've got our vault we've still
got the hole wait wait wait wait wait
wait wait we got the hole here wait whoa
huh
didn't know i could do this well we got
the hole that mumbo made here
but he's rebuilt his chair
and and the chair still up there no i
don't think so mumbo if you leave the
meeting room with your giant flying
chair yeah look you can't have two
chairs look you've you've made your bed
now you've got to to sleep in it so
you've got to be careful with flying
no we're not having this mumbo so you've
you've had your time you've done your
thing you've left the building you've
from now on the meeting is you are up
there we are down here and
you get to sit on the button again
that's the rules mumbo and i want to
make my chair a little bit bigger now
you know now that we're here i can make
i can make mine a little bit bigger just
just give it a couple of wings you have
been relegated mumbo we might come back
later and make make our chair even
bigger
but for now we've got to stay on task
there was a beacon here but that one's
gone you can't leave beacons unattended
basically they just vanish because
people need them in different locations
all right so let's go back down into the
bunker and start setting this up we're
actually going to need more than one
beacon we're gonna need like a mega
beacon to give us all of the different
regenerations and stuff
okay so this is the middle here
and we've got to make a couple of
beacons
here i believe
i always forget how big beacons are i'm
just gonna have to guesstimate
so the beacon is actually gonna cause a
little bit of an issue right because it
produces a beam it needs skylight
that is actually kind of a problem so we
might need to have them off by default
and then have a panic button to turn
them all on
because otherwise everyone's just going
to know where the bunker is and we want
to keep this relatively secret from the
other hermits especially as at some
point
they're going to die in the game of
demise and then this place just becomes
an easy target for pranks so keeping
this secret is quite important there we
go that should do it
so i've actually got to break through
here
all the way up to skylight
but
unfortunately i have no idea
what's directly above
it's actually right next to the river so
at some point we'll have to create i'm
gonna need some redstone help i need i
need iskal or someone to help me out on
this project so we're gonna cover that
up for now
but we're gonna make it so that this
beacon
will have access to the skylight with
the press of a button and it should
automatically turn on and provide us
with what we need so now all we need to
do is pretty much exactly the same over
here but for this side so that we have
multiple beacons it's not the most
efficient way i could just double up on
those but i kind of want the symmetry of
this room to be maintained
all right we're out of beacon materials
but this is actually coming along really
nicely and i think with a little bit of
time and effort we can make this not
only safe and secret but
really formidable
this will see us through to the end of
the game of demise and this is actually
conveniently located that we can link it
up to a lot of the other things that
we've got like we can link it up to
sahara for secret exits we can link it
up to my base there's so much we can do
with this
and when we actually get to the main
room the main area down there i'm gonna
make that special it's gonna be maybe a
bit more cave-like than this
but this is just the welcome to the
architects bunker here it's actually so
secret that the other architects don't
even know it exists
so part one of the bunker is pretty much
complete we've got the room there's not
a lot filled in it but i think that's
probably where we're gonna have to leave
this project it may not look
like i've done a lot but actually
excavating and replacing all the walls
with concrete making the concrete it's
all very very time consuming but this is
a fantastic start to a fantastic mini
game this is going to keep us safe in
the game of demise and if we do things
properly and if you guys can
keep a secret then this bunker will
become a safe haven
so let's leave for now and we'll come
back to this in the next episode i have
to stop flying like that because
it's dangerous gold armor doesn't go
that far in all of this
and most importantly i need to remember
to cover up the entrance one full step
and people will find this really easily
so my checklist for next episode is
trying to make a cool redstone entrance
somewhere around here because that will
drop down into the middle
and then i need to figure out some
redstone contraptions over here for the
the area that's going to be the beacon
use and then we need to extend the whole
thing later on as well so there's pretty
much there's plenty to do and they won't
even realize the other hermits won't
realize that underneath sahara is even
more sahara the other option is of
course that i just die
very very quickly
and then the bunker becomes absolutely
useless
but it looks like we have survived a
full episode and as far as i'm aware
none of the hermits have perished just
yet oh treasure token
they're they're getting a lot harder to
find now but every now and again
i see them
another token for the collection
there's still loads of pickles
everywhere in the shopping district
whatever happened to the that thing
speaking of which i don't think anyone's
bought any pickles since i made this
pretty much i haven't even checked this
shop
all the pickles are gone the heck
someone's taken all the pickles but they
haven't paid me i believe that's that's
thievery
that is um
not okay someone's taking all the
pickles to be fair i haven't really
checked in a long time but
doesn't excuse a pickle thief or maybe
it was the salmon ghost maybe the salmon
ghost stole it all
so i think that is all for today's
episode we actually got a lot done so
many people are involved in the game of
demise we have started our own bunker we
had a little trap that wasn't a trap in
our base and we've got some pretty big
plans for everything oh and patriaran's
cave is a bit of a mess
but looks like we've got a lot to do in
the next few episodes to get everything
set up
and i saw people guessing a lot of you
decided that i was gonna die first
well
it could still be me but i
my hope not
so i actually think that scar will be
the first to go he he dies a lot in this
game but we'll see
we'll see thank you very much for
watching everyone i hope you enjoyed
today's episode of hermitcraft and i
will see you in the next one good bye
i really hope this is water